Preliminary Inventory of the Mueller and Graeff Photographic Poster Collection, ca. 1914-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Mueller and Graeff Photographic Poster Collection,
ca. 1914-1945
XX250
Mueller and Graeff
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs of posters, relating primarily to Germany during World Wars I and II, German political events in the interwar period, and the Spanish Civil War. Includes posters from the Soviet Union, France, and a number of other countries.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; France.; Germany.; Germany--History--20th century--Posters.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Spain.; Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939--Posters.; Posters.
Container List
- Die Entwicklungsgeschichte des Plakates (Box 1)
  - Einführung
  - Der Begründer des Plakates "Chéret" und seine Zeitgenossen
  - Das deutsche Plakat von "Süttrelin" 1895
  - Die Bahnbrecher der deutschen Plakatkunst bis zum Jahre 1905
  - Plakate aus der Zeit von 1905-1914
  - Der Weltkrieg 1914-1918
  - Die Revolution 1918/1919 und die Nationalversammlung
  - Neue Ausdrucksformen
  - Die Photographie im Plakat
  - Verschiedene Sachgebiete aus der Zeit von 1920-1952
  - Das Plagiat
- Werbung am und im Verkehrsmittel
- Der Weltkrieg 1914-1918 Deutschland
  - Mobilmachung
  - Finanzen
    - 1-9 Kriegsanleihe
    - Sparkarten und Kriegsanleihe
    - allgemein
  - Wirts chaft
    - Sammlung von Material
    - Landwirtschaft
    - Ernährung
    - Private Wirtschaftswerbung
  - Sozialpolitik
    - Statstiken
    - Spenden für Heer und Marine
    - Schwestern, Invaliden und Hinterbliebene
    - Kriegsgefangene
    - Spenden allgemein
    - Religiöse Propaganda
  - Geistige Betätigung
    - Ausstellungen
    - Theater und Kino
  - Politik
    - Gegen Feindstaaten
    - Kriegsschuldfrage
    - Vaterlandspartei
    - Spione
    - Luftschutz
    - Statistiken
    - Wehr-und Dienstpflicht
  - Der Zusammenbruch
    - Illegale Flugblätter
    - Für und Gegen den Streik
  - Durchhaltepropaganda
    - Stärkung des Durchhaltewillens
    - Beginn der Revolution
- Der Weltkrieg 1914-1918. Neutrale, Feindstaaten und Verbündete
  - Brasilien
  - Canada
  - England
  - Frankreich
    - Kriegsanleihen
    - Anleihen allgemein
    - Wirtschaft
    - Sozialpolitik
    - Geistige Betätigung
    - Politik
    - Durchhaltepropaganda
  - Holland
  - Italien
  - Russland
  - Schweiz
  - Ungarn
  - U.S.A.
- Revolution und Bürgerkrieg (Box 2)
  - Die deutsche Revolution 1918
  - Rätezeit München 1919
  - Spanische Wahl 1936
    - Volksfront
    - Katalonien/Linkspartei
    - Nationale Partei
    - Syndikalisten
    - Spanisch Marokko/Liksp.
    - Unabhängige Republikaner
  - Spanischer Bürgerkrieg 1937
    - Rot-Spanien
    - National Spanien
    - Winterhilfe, Mutter und Kind
    - Rot Spanien in Frankreich
  - Sowjetunion
- Die Nationalversammlung 1919
  - Regierungsplakate
  - Sozialdemokraten
  - Mehrheitssozialisten
  - Unabhängige Sozialdemokraten
  - Deutsch Demokratische Partei
  - Zentrum
  - Württembergische Bürgerpartei
  - Militärisches
    - Freikorps
    - Reichswehr
    - Grenzschutz
  - Gegen Bolschewismus
- Maueranschläge 1918-1925 (Box 3)
  - Regierungspropaganda
  - Kriegsgefangenen Ausliefe
  - Kriegsgefangene
  - Gewaltfrieden
  - Schwarze Schmach
  - Flüchtlingsfürsorge
  - Für und Gegen den Streik
  - Kampf vor dem Reichstag
  - Sozialisierung
  - Gewerkschaften
  - Ablieferung von Waffen
  - Arbeitsbeschaffung
  - Kriegsentschädigung
  - Liga für Menschenrechte
- Kapp Putsch 1920. Max Hoelz 1921
  - Neue Parteien und Organisat
  - Ruhe und Disziplin
  - Zu den Wahlen
  - Wirtschaft
  - Wien Spende
- Abstimmungs - und Grenzgebiete
  - Oberschlesien
  - Ost-und Westpreussen
  - Schleswig
  - Schleswig Holstein
  - Oberschlesien
  - Rhein und Ruhr
  - Saargebiet
  - Elsass Lotringen
  - Volksopfer Rhein und Ruhr
  - Polen
  - Oestereichisch Deutscher V
- Deutsche Wahlplakate
- Reichspräsidentenwahl 1925
  - Hindenburg
  - Thälmann
  - Marx
  - Braun
- Volksentscheid 1926
- Fürstenenteignung
  - Gegen
  - Für
- Volksbegehren und Entscheid
- Panzerkreuzer 1928
- Volksbegehren und Entscheid
- Young Plan 1929
- Reichspräsidentenwahl 1932
  - Hitler
  - Hindenburg
  - Duesterberg
  - Thälmann
- Volksentscheid 1933
- Wahl 1936
- Alte Sozialdemokratische Partei
- Bauern-und Weingärtner Bund
- Bayerische Volkspartei
- Christlich Sozialer Volksdienst
- Deutsch Demokratische Partei
- Deutsch Nationale Volkspartei
- Deutsch Republikanischer Volsbund
- Deutsche Volkspartei
- Konservative Volkspartei
- Kommunistische Partei
- National Demokratische Partei
- National Sozialistische Deutsche
- Arbeiter Partei
- Republikaner (Box 4)
- Sozialdemokratische Partei
- Vereinigte Sozialdemokratische Partei
- Syndikalisten
- Unabhängige Sozialdemokratische Partei
- Volksrechtspartei
- Wirtschafts Partei
- Zentrum
- Rote-und Arbeiterhilfe
- Gegen § 218
- Iternationale Tage
- 1. Mai Plakate
- Wahlabzeichen- und Kosten
- Politische Plakate aller Länder
  - Dänemark
  - England
  - Frankreich
  - Guatemala
  - Irland
  - Japan
  - Oestereich
  - Polen
  - Portugal
  - Rumänien
  - Schweden
  - Slowakei
- Werkrieg 1939-1945
  - Deutsche Kriegsplakate
  - Feindliche Flugblätter